Ella Reeve Bloor Papers, 1890-1979
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Ella Reeve Bloor papers
1890-1979
1910-1940
Bloor, Ella Reeve, 1862-1951
MS 19
13 boxes (5 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Labor organizer, radical, Socialist, and Communist. Papers illuminate Bloor's experiences as labor organizer, her work for the Socialist and Communist parties, her support for the Daily Worker, women's rights, and other causes. Materials include pamphlets, speeches, writings, photographs, and clippings. Correspondents include Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Bill Haywood, and other notable radicals.
Ella Reeve Bloor, popularly known as "Mother Bloor," was noted for her energetic organizing work on behalf of labor, communism, socialism, and radical causes from the 1910s to the 1930s. "Mother Bloor" was born in 1862 on Staten Island, New York. She married Lucien Ware in 1881 and gave birth to six children between 1882 and 1892. In 1895, Bloor published Three Little Lovers of Nature. The following year, she divorced Ware and in 1897, she married Louis Cohen. In the brief span of her second marriage, Bloor had two sons and published Talk about Authors and Their Works for young adults. Bloor was an activist in the suffrage movement during the 1880s and 1890s. In 1901, she joined the Socialist Party and approximately a year later she divorced Cohen. Partnered with Richard Bloor in 1906 to investigate Chicago's meat packing industry, Bloor took her colleague's name despite the fact that they were never married. Throughout the 1910s-30s, Bloor was an advocate for political prisoners and conscientious objectors as well as an organizer of mining, textile, and farming strikes. She ran for Lieutenant Governor of New York on the socialist ticket in 1918 and participated in the formation of the Communist Party of the U.S.A. in 1919. Two years later, she served as a union delegate to the Second International. Upon her return from the Soviet Union, Bloor hitchhiked throughout the United States while writing articles for the Daily Worker. In 1930, she married Andrew Omholt, her third husband. Seven years later, Bloor returned to the Soviet Union for the twentieth anniversary celebration of the October Revolution. When Bloor returned to the United States she retired to April Farm, Pennsylvania in 1937. Three years later, she published her autobiography, We Are Many. In her early eighties, Bloor undertook a campaign against fascism between 1942 and 1945. In 1951, Bloor died at the age of 89.
For more information, please refer to the biographical essay by Thomas and Richard Edwards in Notable American Women: The Modern Period.
The Ella Reeve Bloor Papers consist of 5.5 linear feet of personal and professional correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, memorabilia, and printed ephemera. The documents span the years 1896 to 1979 and are particularly strong from the late 1910s through the early 1940s. This collection documents most major events of her life except those of her very early career and the investigation of the Chicago meat-packing industry for Upton Sinclair.
There is material throughout the collection related to both her family and many notable colleagues such as Earl Browder, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, William Bross Lloyd, William Foster, Lem Harris, Bill Haywood, Paul Robeson and many others.
This collection is organized into six series:
I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
II. CORRESPONDENCE
III. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
IV. ORGANIZATIONS
VI. PHOTOGRAPHS
V. SUBJECT FILES
OVERSIZE MATERIALS
MICROFILM
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
Additional Formats
The previous owner of the collection prepared a microfilm edition of biographical clippings and correspondence that replicates approximately two-thirds of the collection. It is available through interlibrary loan and is accessible through an index of events and proper names.
History of the Collection
The bulk of the Ella Reeve Bloor Papers were purchased by the Sophia Smith Collection in 1981 from Thomas and Richard Edwards, who had purchased them from the Carl Reeve family. Additional items not included in the original purchase were donated by the Edwards brothers or by Ann Reeve.
Search Terms
Communism--Newspapers--United States--History--Sources; Communists--United States--History--Sources; Labor leaders--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Labor movement--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Communist Party of the United States of America--History--Sources; Radicals--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Socialist Party (U.S.)--History--Sources; Soviet Union--History--Sources; Women--Suffrage--United States-History--Sources; Women and socialism--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Women in labor movement--United States--History--20th century; Bloor, Ella Reeve, 1862-1951; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley; Foster, William Z., 1881-1961; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973; Harris, Lement, 1904-; Haywood, Big Bill, 1869-1928; Lloyd, William Bross, 1908-; Nearing, Scott, 1883-; O'Hare, Kate Richards, 1877-1948; Omholt, Andrew, 1883-1969; Reeve, Carl, 1900-; Reeve, Richard, 1898-; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976; Strong, Anna Louise, 1885-1970; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Ware, Harold M., 1890-1935; Ware, Hamilton Disbrow, 1892-
Additional Information
Related Material
Cassette of Richard Edward's speech at Women and Work Conference (3/8/84), College Archives.
Published writings by Bloor in the Communism Collection; and the Countries Collection (Soviet Union).
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL 1918-1969, 1 linear ft.
  This series is comprised of material relating to Ella Reeve Bloor and some of her family members. It includes invitations, published programs, brochures, writings about Bloor, the scrapbook from her 80th birthday tour in 1842, letters of condolence, and tributes from 1936 to 1962. Of the clippings, those from the 1930s are especially interesting because they document her midwestern organizing activities and her arrest in 1935. Other significant items include a short diary entry, handbills, advertisements, the warrant for her arrest in 1920, itineraries from the 1920s to 1942, and her FBI file.
  The biographical material regarding various family members includes Andrew Omholt's obituaries, Carl Reeve's birth certificate, and a written report by his daughter, Carla. There is also printed material about Bloor's son, Hamilton Disbrow Ware, her daughter, Helen Ware, and Helen's daughter, Herta Geer. There are two folders of material related to Harold Ware with some reports and articles from his files.
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE circa 1890s-1979, 2 linear ft.
  This series is organized in two sections, Family and Friends and associates.
  Both sections contain outgoing correspondence from Bloor and incoming correspondence from family, friends and associates, and between family members. The letters to her family were written during her extensive travels. In these letters she describes the people she encountered and the events in which she was involved. For example, there are detailed accounts of early organizing efforts on behalf of Michigan miners in 1928 and farmers in the Dakotas from 1930 to 1933. Also of interest are her letters describing her campaigns against the executions of Sacco and Vanzetti in 1927 and against fascism during the second World War. Other interesting accounts concern her trips to Russia in 1921-22 and 1937, her 1925 hitchhiking tour for the Daily Worker, and her arrest in Omaha in 1935. The activities of Carl Reeve and Harold Ware, also devoted communists, are documented in their letters.
  While Bloor's correspondence between with her friends and associates is not particularly voluminous with any single individual, a wide variety of noted radicals are represented. Her correspondents include Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Earl Browder, William Bross Lloyd, William Foster, Lem Harris, Bill Haywood, Woody Guthrie, Scott Nearing, Kate Richards O'Hare, Anna Louise Strong, Norman Thomas, Anita Whitney, Emmet "Pat" Cush, and others.
- SERIES III. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS 1899-1944, .4 linear ft.
  This series contains a small number of manuscript notes and speeches as well as a photocopy of Bloor's Talk about Authors and Their Works (1899). Of particular interest are the handbills and advertisements for Bloor's speaking engagements between 1916 and 1942.
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS circa 1896-1951, .4 linear ft.
  This series is largely comprised of correspondence and printed material from a number of organizations directly related to or affiliated in some way with the labor, communist, and socialist movements in the United States. With the exception to the material pertaining to the Communist Party, the bulk of this material represents Bloor's involvement in organizations between 1918 and 1921.
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES 1919-1966, .4 linear ft.
  This series contains printed material, newspaper clippings, and correspondence Bloor collected on subjects such as the Soviet Union and the philosophy and practice of conscientious objection to war.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
  - General
    - Biographical descriptions, 1932, 1934, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Diary entries, 1921-22, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Expenses and receipts, 1918-19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Itineraries, circa 1920s-30s, 1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - List of names, 1917-19, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Warrant for arrest, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Birthday celebrations
    - General: correspondence, newspaper clippings, press releases, and printed material, 1937-48 (Box 1, Folder 8-13)
    - 80th birthday tour scrapbook, 1942
      - Invitations, publicity, and notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Visual images (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Cards and telegrams (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Programs and tributes (Box 1, Folder 17-17a)
      - Publicity (Box 1, Folder 18-18a)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 20-20a)
  - 45th anniversary of labor activities: program, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Writings about Bloor
    - Articles and newspaper clippings (includes obituaries), 1919, 1933-59, 1973, 1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Heroines, by Sasha Small and Mother Bloor, by Ann Barton, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - FBI Files, 1919-51 (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
  - Memorial addresses and tributes, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters of condolence (majority addressed to Elizabeth Gurley Flynn), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 100th anniversary of Bloor's birth: correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Family
    - Omholt, Andrew: obituaries, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Reeve, Carl and Carla: birth certificate and report, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ware, Hamilton Disbrow (Buzz): campaign material, obituaries, and article re: Jimmie Ware (son), 1939, 1945, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ware, Harold
      - Personal records of activities in the Soviet Union, 1925-27 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Reports and articles, 1923-32 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ware, Helen and Herta Geer: printed material, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  Correspondence authored by such distinguished figures as Albert Einstein can also be found in SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS.
  - Family
    - Outgoing
      - Cohen, Louis, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - "My Darling," circa 1890s (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Omholt, Andrew, circa 1940s (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Reeve, Ann, 1936-48 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Reeve, Carl (and family)
        - 1918, 1930-39 (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
        - 1940-50, undated (Box 4, Folder 1-18)
      - Reeve, Carla, 1940-45 (Box 4, Folder 19-24)
      - Reeve, Carla and Susan (grandchildren), 1946-50, undated (Box 4, Folder 25-29)
      - Reeve, Charles (brother), 1942-47 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Reeve, Richard (and family), 1909, 1917-50, undated (Box 5, Folder 2-18)
      - Schwartz, Andy and Herta (grandchildren), 1930s, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Ware, Hamilton Disbrow (Buzz), 1924-40, undated (Box 6, Folder 2-4)
      - Ware, Harold, 1920-32, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
        [see also Friends and associates - Outgoing, Harris, Lem and Kay]
      - Ware, Helen, 1911-43, undated (Box 6, Folder 6-10)
      - Ware, Jessica Abt (Harold Ware's widow), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Ware, Lucien, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Unidentified family, 1916-50, undated (Box 6, Folder 13-17)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Incoming
      - Aunt Lydia to Carl Reeve, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Cohen, Louis to Richard Reeve, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Geer, Herta to Bloor, 1940s (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Horowitz, Sid to Carl Reeve, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Omholt, Andrew
        - to Bloor, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 23)
        - to Richard Reeve and Helen Ware, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 24)
        - from others (not family), 1957, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Reeve, Ann to Bloor, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Reeve, Carl
        - to Bloor, 1915-18, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 27)
        - to Carla Reeve, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 28)
        - to Patricia A. Reeve, 1976-79 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Reeve, Carla and Susan to Ann Reeve, 1946-49 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Reeve, Carla
        - to Bloor, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - from others (not family), 1941, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Reeve, Celia to Ann Reeve, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Reeve, Hamilton Disbrow (brother) to Bloor, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Reeve, Hattie (sister) to Bloor and Helen Ware, 1911, 1918, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Reeve, Janice to Bloor, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Reeve(?), Lucy to Madelen and R.C. Reeve, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Reeve, Richard
        - to Bloor, 1917-45, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - to Carl Reeve, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 10)
        - to Celia Reeve, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 11)
        - to Helen Ware, 1909, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 12)
        - from others (not family), 1926, 1929-30, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Ware, Edith to Bloor, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Ware, Hamilton Disbrow
        - to Bloor, 1919, 1928-43 (Box 7, Folder 15)
        - to Richard Reeve, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Ware, Harold
        - to Bloor, 1915-18 (Box 7, Folder 17)
        - to Helen Ware, 1909-11 (Box 7, Folder 18)
        - to Lucien Ware, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 19)
        - from others (not family), 1932-33 (Box 7, Folder 20)
        - Unidentified, 1923, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Ware, Helen
        - to Bloor, 1914-30 s, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 22)
        - to Richard Reeve, 1940-52, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Ware, Judy to Anne Reeve, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Friends and associates
    - Outgoing
      - Allen, James, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Anstrom, Otto, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Barnes, J. Mahlon, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Bain, Frank and Mildred, 1946, undated (Box 7, Folder 27a)
      - Blain, Fritz, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - "Brothers and sisters," 1930 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Burlak, Anne, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Caplan, Richard, 1920s (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Chamberlin, Lowell, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Cohen, Victor, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - "Dearest children" (not family), 1949 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Donshin, Sam, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Harris, Lem and Kay, 1933-34, 1943-48, undated (Box 7, Folder 36-38)
      - Herbst, Josephine, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Schirmer, D.B., 1942 (Box 7, Folder 39a)
      - Whitney, Anita, 1937, 1942, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Unidentified, 1922, 1942, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Incoming
      - Amter, Israel, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Baer, Elizabeth, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Bain, Frank and Mildred (Walt Whitman group in Toronto), 1918-19, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Balcome, Joseph and Roz, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 45)
      - Ballard, Edith A., 1937 (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - Berkwitz, D., 1919 (Box 7, Folder 47)
      - Bortells, Sophia R., 1919 (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Bronson, Oliver Hart, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 49)
      - Browder, Earl, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - Brown, Harvey Dee, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Brown, T.J., 1919 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - Bush, William L., 1918 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Byrnes, Elinor, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Cadwallader, T. Algernon, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - Caplan, Leo, 1918-19 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - Cowl, Margaret, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - Cowans, Margaret, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - Cush, Emmett Pat, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Dana, Harry, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - Davis, Martha, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley (includes letter from Alice Park), 1919, 1944-45, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Ford, James W., 1944 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Freeman, Helen, circa 1917-18 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Goebel, Margaret, circa 1910-12 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Greenhalph, Kate, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Guthrie, Woody, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Harris, Kay and Lem (includes letter to Ann Reeve), 1935, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Held, Amie, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Hilbert, Clara (includes correspondence to Richard Reeve and her daughter), 1917-31 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Hillquit, Morris, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Hoefler, M.F., 1918 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Holmes, John Haynes, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Hunt, Alice Riggs, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Irwin, Edith, 1929-30 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Johnstone, E., 1946 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Jordon, Franklin, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Kolchy, Mildred, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Krumbien, Margaret, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Kuyma, Joe, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Levine, Hyman, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Lewis, Lena Morrow, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Lloyd, William Bross and L.M. Lloyd, 1914, 1918-19 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Lochner, Louis, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 23)
        [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS -Liberty Defense Union]
      - Lunde, Theodore, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - McDonough, Frank, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Marblestone, Eli, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Marians, Grace, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Massey, Helen, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Mewmaw, A.E., 1919 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Millington, E.J., 1919 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Morse, Frank, 1930s (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Myers, Bettie, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - O'Connor, Jessie Lloyd, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - O'Hare, Kate Richards to F. O'Hare (copies sent to Bloor), 1919 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Patuande, E., 1914 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Peake, May, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Popper, Lilly, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Reefer, Z., 1919 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Relis, H., 1918 (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - Roewer, George E., 1919 (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - Rothman, Frank H., 1918 (Box 8, Folder 41)
      - Sager, J. H., 1918 (Box 8, Folder 42)
      - Saunders, Henry S. (Whitman group in Toronto), 1917 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      - Sejsworth, Charles F. (Whitman group in Toronto), 1917 (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - Shapovalov, Mary, 1920s (Box 8, Folder 45)
      - Sharp, Kate, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 46)
      - Sharts, Joseph W., 1918, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 47)
      - Shore, Viola Brothers, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 48)
      - Smith, Leita F., 1918 (Box 8, Folder 49)
      - Strickland, Fred, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - Thomas, Evan, undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
      - Traubel, Horace (Whitman group in Toronto), 1918 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      - Upton, Harriet Taylor, undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
      - Van Eaton, Kate, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 54)
      - Vogt, Frederick J., 1918 (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Wanamaker, Lillian, undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Whitehead, Marjorie, undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - Whitney, Anita, 1929-30s, 1944, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 58)
      - Wilga, Fedor (associated with "Technical Aid to Soviet Union" and was in America to learn methods of tractor farming), 1917-19, 1923-37, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 59)
      - Wilson, Oliver, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Winter, Charles and Alice, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Greeting cards, 1930s-40s, undated (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Unidentified from Ernest, 1918, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Unidentified from Laura, 1917-19 (Box 8, Folder 64)
      - Unidentified, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 65)
- SERIES III. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
  - Handbills and advertisements for speaking engagements, 1916-42, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Writings, speeches and notes, 1913-44, undated (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Talk about Authors and Their Works(photocopy) by Ella Reeve Ware, Chicago, A. Flanagan & Co. 1899 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Three Little Lovers of Nature by Ella Reeve Ware, Chicago, A. Flanagan & Co. 1895 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - We Are Many (autobiography), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Book jacket, We Are Many (autobiography), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America: correspondence, 1918-19 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bridgeport Central Labor Union: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Canadian Labor Party: printed material, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Church of the Messiah: booklets, printed material, and yearbook, 1918-19 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Civic Club, New York: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Communist Party of the U.S.A.
    - General: campaign program, correspondence, printed material, and publicity, 1930(?), 1936, 1949, 1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - District #9: correspondence, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Eastern Pennsylvania: correspondence and delegate card, 1944, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Political Association: correspondence, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Political Bureau: correspondence, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Daily Worker, editor: correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Democratic County Committee: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists: correspondence (Albert Einstein), 1947 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Eugene V. Debs Club: correspondence, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Fabian Club of Boston: meeting schedule, printed material, and publicity, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Farmers National Relief Conference: manifesto, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Farmers Union: bulletin, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Ferdinand C. Smith Testimonial Dinner Committee: correspondence, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Free Religious Association of America: printed material, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Free Speech Committee of N.S.W.: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - General Relief Committee Textile Strikers: booklet, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Greater New York Tenant League: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Intercollegiate Socialist Society: correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - International Association of Machinists: correspondence, 1914, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers: journal, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - International Forum Association: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - International Labor Defense: correspondence and printed material, 1944, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Kings County Communist Party: correspondence, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Labor Defense Council: correspondence, 1918, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - League of Democratic Control: minutes, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - League of Radical Leaders: outline, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Liberty Defense Union: printed material, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 32)